Maciej Sawicki

saw.maciej@gmail.com +48 696 022 099 maciejsawicki.com

Summary

Senior UX/UI designer with more than 10 years of experience in SASS products, both B2C and B2B. Expertise in User Centered Design methodology. Specializing in prototyping and user research for complex products. Conducted over 200 usability tests on own prototypes. Exceptional ability to find simple solutions for complex problems. Highly productive and always on time.

Experience

Espeo Software • 1 year (2021 - 2022)

Lead Product Designer

Rachuneo • 2 years (2019 - 2021) CTO / UX Designer / Front-end developer

Currency One • 4 years (2017 - 2021)

UX Designer

Egnyte • 3 years (2014 - 2017)

UX Designer

Blueberry Communication Group • 2 yrs 4 mos (2012 - 2014)

Head of Strategic Planning & UX Designer

Education

SGH Warsaw School of Economics

Master's degree in Management & Marketing Listed among the top 10% of students

Skills

Prototyping

User research

••••

Problem solving

....

Graphic design

••••

PM

HTML/CSS

JS/jQuery

••••

Workshops

••••

Tools

Webflow

••••

Figma

••••

UXPin

AdobeXD

••••

Photoshop

••••

Detailed experience and projects

$\mbox{ View portfolio presentation} \rightarrow \mbox{ }$

Espeo Software • Current • 1 year Lead Product Designer

Responsible for business development of all product design services of Espeo software house:

- Strategic planning
- · Team building and recruitment
- Guiding team members and subcontractors
- · Conducting design workshops
- Supporting sales
- Estimating budgets

Hands-on experience with multiple UX projects with Espeo clients:

- Fintech SaaS · Member of a scrum development team for a core user flow for a Swiss banking platform
- Genesis · Internal tool · Prototyping a complex meta CMS tool for a worldwide online gambling platform in a user centered design process
- Awake.ai · Logistics · Prototyping & user testing selected features for a Finnish port management platform
- Laboratorium Marzeń · Non-profit · designing a UX strategy of a mobile app for parents of premature babies
- VeganNation · Maps/Fintech/Blockchain · Guiding & supervising
 UI/UX design for a community & mobile payment platform
- Sovereign.ai · Data & Intelligence · Prototyping an innovative data analytics platform with a gaming-like user experience and UI
- SISAA · Fintech · Designing interaction and art directing an innovative wealth management mobile app

Google Analytics

JIRA

••••

also:

Google Ads

Google Optimize

Firebase

Justinmind Prototyper

Swimlanes.io

Balsamiq

Vegas

Logic Pro

Ableton Live

Lightroom

Illustrator

Git

Gulp build system

ITunes Connect

Languages

Polish (native)



English (C1)

••••

BugBug.io • Sideproject • 1 year Freelance UX Designer / Consultant Sector: SASS / No-code

Co-creating a browser based testing automation platform BugBug.io.

Accomplishments:

- Fully prototyped a complex custom SASS product in Webflow, with complex interactions
- Solved hundreds of non-trivial design problems
- Received positive reviews for product simplicity, especially compared to competitive solutions

Currency One • 4 years

UX Designer / Product Owner

Sector: Fintech

Full-time UX designer for two leading currency exchange platforms in Poland: Walutomat.pl and Internetowykantor.pl.

Accomplishments:

- Introduced User Centered Design and user interviews to this company
- Organized usability tests 2 3 times a week to learn user needs, identify usability issued and get insights for business strategy.
- Managed important strategic projects as a product owner (ex. mobile apps that received excellent reviews)
- Co-created the InternetowyKantor.pl branding refresh
- Contributed to measurable results: better funnel conversion, remarkably high NPS scores, positive user feedback on product intuitiveness.

Rachuneo • 2 years

CTO / UX Designer / Front-end developer

Sector: Fintech / Start-up

Co-created Rachuneo.pl - the first online service that helps people to compare prices for electricity, gas, internet, multimedia and easily switch to a new supplier.

Accomplishments:

- Created the product from scratch, analyzed market, regulatory limitations, conducted user interviews, validated branding ideas.
- Designed and delivered a working lean-startup MVP that is still used in production, including the mathematical algorithms for energy price comparison.
- Worked part-time in a CTO-like role being responsible for managing a team of external developers, designing new features, and often personally coding their front-end.
- Efficiently handled numerous start-up responsibilities:
 - o all the design / prototyping / user testing
 - o all the technology and architecture
 - IT outsourcing
 - o front-end coding
 - o R&D for new business development
 - data analytics
 - marketing operations (Google Ads, affiliate programs, FB ads etc.)

Egnyte • 3 years

UX Designer

Sector: file sync and sharing

Full-time UX designer for business-to-business SASS service based in Silicon Valley.

Accomplishments:

- Improved user experience of Egnyte's file sync and sharing enterprise solutions: from little details to high level problems
- Introduced usability testing to the company and managed to smooth out the design decision-making process
- Worked with an overseas design team and advocated User
 Centered Design as a strategic approach to the design process
- Worked closely with developers and product owners to ensure high quality of usability & UI design
- Introduced usability testing to the company and managed to smooth out the design decision-making process
- Designed the UI for a totally new product Egnyte Protect
- Improved the visual appeal of the products

• Designed highly-interactive prototypes for multiple platforms: web app, native Windows, native MaOS, mobile apps

Blueberry Communication Group • 2 yrs 4 mos

Head of Strategic Planning & UX Designer

Sector: digital marketing / advertising

Accomplishments:

- Managed multiple projects for well-known FMCG brands like L'Oreal, Nestle, Halls
- Created several successful UX designs that delighted agency clients (ex. Orange mobile website).
- Provided leadership for new business projects, market research, strategic recommendations, creative team guidance, brainstorming, sales presentations
- Introduced wireframing, usability testing to clients
- Designed several successful sales promotion mechanisms

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in the application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process in accordance with Art. 6 paragraph 1 letter a of the Regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council (EU) 2016/679 of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).